Episode 13
The Misanthrope and the Nigh Future
Uchami, what's that?
A piece of straw.
My assignment is
to use this to trade with.
Like the tale of the Straw Millionaire?
That's right.
At the end, I'll need to trade
for something with the principal.
What's your assignment, Maki?
As for me...
I need to find a hundred truths.
And write them down in this tiny book.
My assignment is getting 5,000
followers on social media!
But how exactly do I gain followers?
Think about how you can
show empathy for others.
Ms. Mirai, do you know
a lot about social media?
I have 124,000 followers!
That's amazing!
Ms. Mirai, could you please
teach me your secrets?
Of course!
Wakaba, what's your assignment?
Mine is to keep a diary.
I need to write at least three things
that happen every day in it.
Mine is making dinners for the dorm!
Nezu, you know how to cook?
Technically speaking...
Your choice of words speaks volumes.
You know how cooking ingredients
taste fine the way they are?
So, well...
I see, so you sneak in some bites.
Tobari, what's your assignment?
I have to compose a song using at least
three instruments I've never played.
Another task on the creative side, huh?
Pretty much.
Okay, your assignments have just begun.
Don't panic and tackle them
at a measured and steady pace.
Understood?
Yes!
Mr. Hitoma, I'm done!
That was fast!
What instruments did you use
that you've never played?
The kazoo, the daxophone,
and the wheelharp!
I don't recognize a single one...
They produce pretty
interesting sounds. Wanna hear?
Oh? Let's see.
Tobari, that's not fair!
Sharing earbuds with Mr. Rei!
I want him to ask me
about my assignment, too!
Oh, how's yours going, Ryuzaki?
I'm not getting any followers at all.
If you ask me, gaining followers is all
about getting people to like you.
I'm fine with Mr. Rei being
the only person who likes me.
Then you won't be able to
complete your assignment.
Why don't you try using your
strengths to draw people in?
Ryuzaki, what do you
think your strengths are?
How much I love you, Mr. Rei!
No, not what I mean.
I like it! Why don't you try that out?
Be serious.
So you mean posting my daily
fantasies about Mr. Rei?
Sounds awesome!
Take a look at my assignment, too.
How are your Straw
Millionaire trades going?
I traded Maki's pen for a photo of Aoi,
which I traded with Konno
from the Aoi Fan Club for some snacks,
which I traded with Machi
for her school notebook,
which I traded with Yuki for some makeup,
which I traded with
Karin for a magic stone.
What's a magic stone?
It's like a piggy bank for magical power.
But no one wants to trade
for this magic stone.
At this rate, I'll end up handing
this rock in to the principal.
You're not handing it in yet?
I'll wait until just before the deadline.
If I trade it for something better,
I can get a better grade.
Oh yeah, how are you doing, Nezu?
It's looking dicey,
but I'm trying my best.
Dicey?
I'm only allowed to taste
a teaspoon's worth as I cook.
After tasting a teaspoon...
I want more and more,
and get withdrawal symptoms...
I even get visions of me stuffing my face!
It's that bad?!
Wakaba, your assignment was a diary?
How's that going?
Quite smoothly.
Since I have to write down three things
that happen every day,
I've learned a lot from it as well.
In what ways?
It's made me interact
with others more, just like I am now.
Mr. Hitoma, I did it!
Okonogi, you had to find a hundred truths.
"The sky is blue."
"Clouds are white."
"This is the thirty-second entry."
"This is the thirty-third."
Okonogi.
Huh?
Give me a second here.
Let me figure out
everything I want to say.
In my opinion, "finding" here
means making new discoveries.
Discoveries?
Are there a hundred discoveries in here?
Sure are!
Okonogi, you like cute things, don't you?
Yeah!
I love everything that's adorbs!
And is that the truth?
Huh? Hmph!
Would you call what
you wrote down cute?
I-It's not adorbs...
So this entry?
It's not the truth...
I hate to say this
after everything you wrote,
but can you find another
hundred truths for me?
I'll do my best...
Mr. Hitoma!
Look, look! I filled it out!
Let's see...
"Macchi's cooking is tasty."
"Tobarin has pretty eyes."
"Prince Waka is cute when she smiles."
"Karin loves Mr. Hitoma."
"Ushami is a hard worker."
"I love my mom."
Oh, there you go.
Do you think these are cutie-cute?
I can tell you really
think these are true.
Yeah, but are they cutie-cute?
Huh? They're...
They're?
They're cutie—I mean, cute.
Thanks!
She's amazing.
Amazing how?
Um...
I mean, it's your fault!
I don't wanna hear that from you!
Let's go.
Yes!
What's going on, you two?
Ugh! It's Usami!
Tsukino, you've got some nerve informally
calling me by my last name
as a beginner class student.
It's not my fault!
Maibara's the one who...
What happened?
Hitoma.
Can you tell us what this is about?
The two of us are a pair for our
group assignment to move up a grade.
We need to do ten things that
make people tell us, "Thank you."
But Maibara wants out of the group!
I didn't say that!
I said I can't go along
with what you're doing!
That's the same thing!
Hey, hold on. Let's calm down.
Why can't you go along with her?
It's not right to cause trouble
for someone in order to help them.
What?
It fulfills the assignment, doesn't it?!
You're not supposed to hide someone's
stuff so you can lend them your own!
I agree. I don't think that's right.
I feel the same way.
What?
If you've got something
to say, out with it.
Usami, don't be too harsh on her.
Why me?
I was just trying
to finish our assignment...
But I think it was wrong
to hide people's belongings.
Wait up!
Are you all right?!
What?
Are you hurt at all?!
No, I'm fine.
That's good to hear.
It's not good at all!
Your graduation assignment!
Don't worry about that.
But because of me...
It's more important
that you didn't get hurt.
Still!
Listen to me!
I'm not so petty as to let
that get me down.
I'm a lot more serious
than that about being here.
Show a little more respect.
I'll start over from scratch,
no matter how many times it may take.
So let me see you start over as well!
I'm sorry...
I'll do my best...
I swear it!
Tell that to Inaho, not me.
I'm sorry, too.
I had made you do everything.
Sorry.
I'm sorry, too.
Hitoma.
Looks like that rock
released its power on its own.
Does that count as unhuman-like behavior?
It was out of your hands,
so I think we'd overlook it...
I'll ask just to be safe.
I thought this would be
the year Usami graduated for sure...
But the item for her assignment is gone.
Mr. Hitoma!
Congratulations!
What's this all about, Principal?!
I forgot to tell you.
This is what it's like whenever
we have someone graduating.
Good work on your graduation
assignments, everyone!
After careful consideration, we've decided
on this year's graduates!
We will have one student
graduating this year.
She's been harder on herself
than anyone else,
facing her goals head-on while diligently
studying and striving all this time.
Despite her tendency
to be just as strict on others,
she has fostered her sense of caring to
become a student who cherishes others.
For these reasons stated...
Sui Usami. You are this year's...
That can't be right!
I never handed in my
graduation assignment!
So... this must be some sort of mistake.
No, this is no mistake.
Then what? I don't need you
to make an exception for me.
That doesn't make me happy!
We received an assignment submission.
An appeal letter, that is.
An appeal letter?
Asking for Sui Usami's
graduation assignment
to be considered complete.
Written by Tsukino Wakuma
from the beginner class.
It says she wants to repay
the kindness you've shown.
Repay me?
To give something back
for what you've done.
As part of the trade
for the piece of straw.
That's just a made-up rationale.
Repaying kindness.
That's what you've always talked about.
Your reason at first to become human was
to repay the kindness a human showed you.
Didn't you teach her how to write those
words for your assignment last year?
And so, this is the final trade.
A ring...
Based on this evaluation...
Sui Usami.
You are this year's graduating student!
Congratulations, Usami.
You can get in touch with this.
Is now the time for that?
But well, I guess I can contact
you once in a while, Hitoma.
This is Sae's card, not mine.
Sae's? Tell me that sooner!
Didn't I promise to hold onto it
until you graduated?
I can't wait to see what
that brat is like all grown up.
Hitoma.
One day, I'll repay your kindness as well.
So make sure you stay healthy until then.
Sure.
We have one student graduating this year.
Yeah.
But there are still five students
in the advanced class,
as well as any students
who move up next year...
Hitoma.
Usami.
There's something I need to say to you.
I enrolled here to become human
and repay Seiko.
Because of that, I couldn't
spend Seiko's last days with her.
That's right.
I'd regretted it.
All this time, I regretted
not staying with Seiko.
I see...
But thanks to you, I managed
to meet Seiko before she left us.
I found a new purpose,
and now I can meet Sae as an adult.
Yeah.
I don't think I'd have managed
to graduate without you.
So Hitoma...
Thank you.
I should thank you, too.
I learned a lot from being
with you as well.
Really?
Yeah.
A teacher does more than just teach.
There's plenty we can learn
from students, too.
Not to mention...
I have plenty of regrets as well.
But I don't ever want to
forget those regrets.
Even though they're bad memories?
Yeah. They're all precious to me.
I won't forget them, either!
Both the good and the bad!
Glad to hear it.
Take care even after I'm gone.
Hitoma, Mirai.
You too, Usami.
Thank you. Take care.
Until we meet again!
Mr. Hitoma.
What is it?
Are they precious to you?
What?
Your regrets, I mean.
I regret some things as well.
Haruna.
Back in high school, I wished
I had never met you, Mr. Hitoma.
And I still do.
What I regret is having met you.
Just now, you said you
won't forget your regrets.
I did.
How awful.
That's way too sad.
I wish you'd forget all
about what happened back then.
I can imagine.
But I won't forget.
Why not?
Even... Even though...
I don't want that...
Sorry.
Stop! Don't apologize!
I won't be able to live with myself!
If you'd never gotten involved with me...
You wouldn't have had to resign!
What? Haruna?
I didn't want to drag you into it, either!
You love your job, don't you?
Even I could tell that much!
You still regret it, don't you?
I told you to forget about it ...
That you didn't need
to let it bother you...
Why? Stop it...
I don't want to bring up
painful memories for you.
I don't want to be
the cause of your regrets.
I'm sorry, Mr. Hitoma...
I apologize for letting
you see me like that.
I was sure you had a grudge against me.
That would never be the case.
If I did, I wouldn't have come here.
Do you remember our last conversation?
You blamed me for taking you seriously
and trying to do the impossible.
That's because...
I wanted to hurt you.
I lied to you on purpose.
I knowingly said those nasty things.
It wasn't me who came up
with the physical discipline, either.
I could never have done that.
Was it Akazawa?
Did Akazawa threaten you?
No!
What Rio did was really awful, but...
The last part wasn't her.
That was of my own volition.
I've always regretted
what I did back then.
I hurt you, and
I wanted to be hurt as well.
Doing that would make you hate me.
Once you hated me, I...
thought I'd be free of the burden.
But that's not what happened at all.
At first, I felt a little better.
I was glad you hated me.
But I ended up hurting you.
For my own temporary relief.
When I thought of it like that,
I started to feel so guilty...
I'm so sorry.
Maybe we're a little bit alike.
What?
It's not your fault, Haruna.
I really am glad I never forgot about you.
Why didn't you forget?
I could never! You meant a lot to me.
You said you regretted it.
Yeah.
I regret it, and I still wonder sometimes
whether there was a better way.
But I got to meet you again,
and maybe that's enough.
Seriously?
Still, thank you.
I'm glad to see you're still
the same as well.
I'll become a teacher just like you!
Director's Office
Mr. Hitoma.
Well done surviving another year.
The end of this year marks
the end of your employment contract.
The both of us would love
to continue to keep you on.
You said it.
It's not easy finding
humans who fit the bill.
So, won't you renew your contract?
I'd like to continue working here as well.
I knew you'd see it that way!
That's good to hear.
There's still a lot more work
I'd like to ask you to do.
Actually, I've found a purpose now.
Hm? What is it?
Seeing through Tobari Haneda's graduation.
Is that right? I hope you pull it off.
Yeah.
Hey, Mr. Hitoma. Do you like humans?
Humans are annoying,
they can't be honest...
They lie all the time,
and almost never stick to their claims.
Their fickle natures cause me
trouble to no end...
But I'm content to live out my life
at the mercy of their whims.
In other words?
I hate humans.
Get involved in practically any way,
and they cause you all sorts of trouble.
But...
That's the part of humans I'll hold
dear as I continue to live with them.
I see.
Translation:
Timing:
Editing and Typesetting:
Quality Control:
Translation Check:
John K.
Andy Ellis
Ashley Barboza
Gabriella Alabanza
Michelle Tymon
That being said...
Will we see the day when Mr. Hitoma
makes Tobari Haneda graduate?
Who can say?
Do you think I can manage to graduate?
You show no interest in
graduating, Lady Shiranui.
And we'd be
in a lot of trouble if you did.
I know that.
What will the next year bring?
Mr. Hitoma.
Teach me more about being human.